家里人还好吗
So how's the family?
挺好的 孩子们都长大了 海莉准备要
Great. Kids are getting so big. Haley's about to go off...
你可以不用使劲收腹了
You can stop holding your stomach in.
-去上大学了 -你坚持锻炼吗
- To college. - You still exercising?
显然啊
Clearly.
我看到克林特·艾斯伍德
I look at a Clint Eastwood
和查克·诺里斯那种体魄 就想着
or Chuck Norris and I think,
我也可以像他们那样健壮...
there's no reason I can't stay tough like..
痒死人家啦
Oh, tickles!
不过
But...
痛吗
That hurt?
不 不太...嗷
No. Not r--ow.
怎么了
What?
应该没大碍 你感觉还好吧
It's probably nothing. You feeling okay?
-很好 -保险起见 做几个检查吧
- Yeah. - Maybe we'll just run a couple of tests, just to be safe.
什么检查呢
What kind of tests?
如果有问题 我会打电话给你的
If there's anything wrong, I'll give you a call.
好
Okay.
房地产市场现在如何
So how's the real estate market doing?
贷款利率很低 正是购房的好时机
Well, interest rates are low, so it's a great time to be a buyer,
如果你是要卖房 那就得
But if you're a seller, you really have to...
卑躬屈膝?
Bend over?
没错 不过房子质量好的话
True, but a quality property is still a quality--
不 我是让你弓腰屈膝
No, no, no. I need you to bend over.
好吧
Oh. Right.
把灯调暗 诺拉·琼斯的音乐调大点
Well, let's dim the lights, crank up the Norah Jones,
速战速决吧
and get this over with.
回来啦 进展如何
Oh, hey. How'd it go?
棒极了 我真为他骄傲
Amazing. I was so proud of him.
谢了 亲爱的
Oh, thanks, honey.
我也挺为自己骄傲的
I'm kind of proud of me, too.
看看他们发给我的
Look at what they gave me.
加州律师专业协会
"California State Bar Association Award
环保法领域 杰出贡献奖
"For Distinguished Service in The Field of Environmental Law."
你真该去看看 他们念到他的名字
You should have seen it. They called his name,
他走上台 发表了很棒的得奖感言
He went up on stage, he gave a great speech.
既谦虚 又鼓舞人心
It was humble, inspirational,
最后还冷冷地幽了一默
with a touch of dry humor at the end.
超级有科林·费斯的范儿
It was very Colin Firth.
谢谢你小卡
Oh, Cam, thank you,
不过 又不是奥斯卡那种大奖
But... it's hardly an Oscar.
在环保法领域
In the environmental law community,
其实就相当于奥斯卡啦
it kinda is an Oscar.
莉莉还好吗 你们俩不会太无聊吧
So how was Lily? I hope you weren't too bored.
你开玩笑吗
Oh, please,are you kidding me?
我可爱和她聊天了 她懂的词比海莉还多
I love talking to her. She knows more words than Haley.
放在那里真好看
Oh, that looks great up there!
此时此刻很崇拜你舅舅吧
How impressed are you with your uncle right now?
崇拜得五体投地
So impressed.
我不想毁了他们的兴致
I didn't wanna ruin their moment
就忍着没说出我得过的各种奖
by telling them how many awards I've gotten,
简而言之
But let's just say
那种大小的奖 我都懒得起床去领
I don't get out of bed for a trophy that size.
该死的
Darn it!
我想发个邮件
I'm trying to send an e-mail.
鼠标却老是卡住
This mouse keeps sticking.
反应那么大 这最多值十块钱
Pretty big reaction. It's 10 bucks, tops.
你正好让我想起昨晚的梦
You just reminded me about my dream last night.
我身处牧场之中 正在下楼梯
I was in the middle of a meadow, coming down a staircase,
突然一只黑老鼠出现了
then suddenly a black mouse showed up.
他停下来 直视我的双眼
He stopped, stared at me in the eyes,
张开他的小嘴
and opened his little mouth.
它说什么了
What did it say?
它还能说什么 杰
What did he say, Jay?
它就是只老鼠 不会说话
He was a mouse. They don't know how to talk.
你现在开始讲逻辑了
Now you're playing logic police?
你还站在牧场的楼梯上呢
You're standing on a staircase in a meadow?
在我们国家 要是有人梦到了黑老鼠
In my country, when somebody dreams about a black mouse,
就意味着有坏事将要发生
It means that something bad is going to happen!
别担心
Ah, don't worry about it.
我梦到了一头预示好运的蓝牛
I dreamt about a lucky blue cow.
-我们就扯平了 -杰
- We're good to go. - Hey, Jay,
这是我明天去打高尔夫球的行头
this is what I'm wearing for golfing tomorrow.
抬头看看 明天别跟我穿撞衫了
Wanted to give you a heads up in case there's some overlap.
你玩的是哪般啊
What are you going for here?
《重返荣耀》里的马特·戴蒙 你没看出来
Matt damon in "Bagger Vance." you didn't get that?
我看出来了 你简直以假乱真
I did. I think you look just like him.
我叫你教我打高尔夫就是为了这个
It's the whole reason I asked you to teach me to golf.
任何能穿得如此拉风的运动 我都愿参加
Any sport where you can wear this, I'm in.
谁呀 都晚上十点了
Who is that? It's 10:00 at night.
-我去开 -等等 盖茨比
- I'll get it. - Hold on, Gatsby.
有人吗 我是哈维尔 开门啊
Hola! It's Javier! Open up!
爸爸
Dad!
我的小冠军
There's my campeon!
他就是你梦中的黑老鼠
There's your black mouse.
哈维尔 你到这儿来干什么
Hola, Javier, what are you doing in town?
我错过了曼尼的生日 而这周正好没事
Well, I missed Manny's birthday, plus I have a free week.
你要待一整周吗
You're staying a week?
赶快让他走
Make that go away.
曼尼 明天
So, Manny, tomorrow,
为了庆祝你长大成人
In honor of you becoming a man,
我带你去看赛马
I am taking you to the racetrack
享受国王的运动
to enjoy the sport of kings, hmm?
太好了
That's so cool!
实际上 曼尼明天要和我去打高尔夫
Actually, Manny and I have plans to play golf tomorrow.
高尔夫 那是给老头子
Golfing? Pfft! That is for old men
和喜欢女人的女人们玩的
and for women who like women.
乖 你老爸大驾光临 我们一起去看赛马
Come on. Your dad is in town. Let's go to the races.
我们能一起去吗
Yeah, can we all go?
抱歉 宝贝 我不行
Ay, no, baby, I can't.
我答应了海莉教她西班牙语
I promised Haley that I was gonna help her with her Spanish.
-不过杰会跟你们一起去的 -什么
- But Jay's going to go with you. - What?
我不会让曼尼和哈维尔单独出去的
I'm not gonna let Manny take off with Javier by himself.
有一次 曼尼6岁时
Once, when Manny was 6,
哈维尔带他去"爱抚动物园"
Javier took him to the petting zoo,
结果我发现
which later, I found out
那是家脱衣舞俱乐部的名字
that was the name of the stripper club.
真正的动物园都比那里干净
A real petting zoo would have been cleaner.
-可我很期待打 -你去定了
- But I was looking forward to playing-- - You're going.
你妈还是老样子
That I don't miss.
那是什么玩意儿啊
Would you look at that?
哦 那个
Oh, yeah, you know,
我自认为我们不是喜欢显摆荣耀的人
I never saw us as trophy on the mantle people,
可你的奖杯放在上面光彩夺目
but yours looked so gosh darned good up there,
我就想 为何不晒出我们的辉煌呢
I figured, why not be proud of what we've done?
巴斯卡特斯春季钓鱼赛第一名
Uh, "First Place, Basscatcrsrs Spring Fish-Off,
密苏里州北部分赛区
Missouri North Division."
2天钓到10条小口黑鲈
2-day total of 10 smallmouth bass
总计34.24磅
weighing 34.24 pounds
最大的是一条4.5磅重鱼王
with a 4 1/2-pound kicker.
所以你打败了其他所有12到17岁的男孩
So you beat all the other boys aged 12 through 17?
当然
Sure did.
看看我们的奖杯
Look at our trophies up there.
我们真是强强结合啊 是不
We're a couple of winners, aren't we?
是吗
Are we?
克莱尔
Claire?
我的剃须刀片呢
Where are all my razor blades?
-没在盒子里吗 -没
- They're not in that box? - No.
可能是用完了
Well, I guess they're gone.
不可能用完
They can't be gone.
我二十几岁时 参加了一个竞赛节目
In my 20s, I went on a game show
赢得了够用一辈子的剃须刀片
and won a lifetime supply of razor blades.
菲尔 时间到了 你的答案是
Okay, Phil, time is up. What is your answer?
抱歉 菲尔
Oh! I'm sorry, Phil.
正确答案是香蕉奶油
The correct answer is banana cream.
香蕉奶油
Banana cream.
香蕉奶油 被你考到了
Banana cream. Well, you got me there, chip.
可你也不会空手而归
But you're not leaving empty-handed, no.
你将获得够用一辈子的
You're going home with a lifetime supply
创世纪牌双面剃须刀片
of Genesis twin-blade razors.
什么 一把剃须刀有两面刀片
What?! Two blades in one razor?
老兄 我从未遇过这等好事
Man, it'll ever get be better than that!
你一定是把它们用完了
You must have used them all up.
它说的是够用一辈子
They said "lifetime supply."
亲爱的 你都用了15年免费剃须刀片了
Honey, you got 15 years of free razor blades.
你已经够赢了 别贪心了
Put that in the "Win" column and move on.
老妈 我朋友沃特能来我们家
Mom, is it okay if my friend Walt comes over
和我一起玩《反叛者3》吗
to play "Rebel Fighters 3"?
宝贝 你不觉得和一个八十岁的老头儿
Honey, don't you think it is a little weird
关系那么好有点奇怪吗
that one of your best friends is an eighty-year-old man?
不 忘年交很有趣 他经历过真正的战争
No, it makes it more fun, because he was in a real war.
他会说些很酷的话
He says cool things like
比如"地狱再会吧 克劳斯"
"See you in hell, Klaus."
我都不知道那话是什么意思
I don't even know what that means.
对了老爸 有个医生打电话来找过你
Oh, hey, dad, some doctor called for you.
桑德弗医生吗
Dr. Sendroff?
对 是他 你当时在洗澡
Yeah, that's it. You're in the shower.
他说什么了
What did he say?
他叫你尽快回电话
He wants you to call him right away.
那就地狱再会吧 克劳斯
Oh, well. See you in hell, Klaus.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不知道
I don't know.
他昨天给我做了一些检查
He ran a few tests on me yesterday.
他说如果有问题会打电话给我
He said he'll call if something was wrong.
现在他打了
And now he's calling.
你好 我是菲尔·邓菲
Hi, this is Phil Dunphy.
桑德弗医生打过电话给我
I'm returning Dr. Sendroff's call
你在开玩笑吗
Are you serious?
-怎么了 -他在去伦敦的飞机上
- What? - He's on a flight to London.
有什么办法可以让我联系到他吗
Um, is there any way I can reach him,
或者 我能和其他什么人谈谈吗
or--uh, uh, someone else I can talk to?
好吧
Okay. Fine.
请告诉他是紧急事件
Please just tell him it's urgent.
谢谢
Thank you.
天呐
Oh, boy.
亲爱的 我相信没事的
Honey, I am sure it's nothing.
克莱尔 我胳膊下酸软无力
Claire, I'm tender under my arm.
也许是卢克用扫帚打到你了
Maybe Luke hit you with his broomstick
就是你们上次玩魁地奇游戏的时候
when you guys play Quidditch.
我飞得多快啊 他没有碰到过我
I'm way too fast he never touched me.
我可以保证 你绝对没事
I can assure you you are perfectly fine.
你的安慰"真有效"
That's very comforting,
你大学专业是市场营销 又不是医学
coming from a marketing major at a party school.
我看好4号马
I like the number 4 horse.
它熟悉这个赛道
He loves this track,
而且它爸爸赢过普里克内斯大奖赛
his dad won the Preakness,
最近三次比赛押它的人都赚了
Last three finishes were in the money.
我看好"米兰达的奇迹"
I like Miranda's miracle.
为什么
Why?
我们班上有个女生叫米兰达
There's this girl Miranda in my class,
她是个美女
and she is really pretty.
如果她也喜欢我 那一定是个奇迹
If she likes me back, it will be a miracle.
你能帮我押两块钱在它身上吗 杰
Would you bet $2 on that one for me, Jay?
没问题 不过你这钱一定是打水漂
Sure, but you are throwing your money away.
你们俩都是
You both are.
7号马才是最终的赢家
The winner of the race will be number 7--
"君之乡"
my hometown.
七号
Number 7...
它多了三磅肥膘
Well, he's carrying 3 extra pounds,
而且它不擅于长跑
And he hates the distance.
那些都是纸上谈兵
Those are just words on a page.
我和那只马对视时
I look the horse in the eye,
它告诉我 它会是赢家
And he tells me... he is the winner.
马会说话吗
Tells ya?
-听上去也许有些疯狂 -无需解释
- Perhaps this will sound crazy. - No need for the qualifier.
不过我确实能感知马的灵魂
But I have always been able to see into the soul of a horse.
绝对是我的天赋 我从不怀疑
It is a gift, and I do not question it.
就像我在银行排队时 总在最短的那条
Just like I always end up on the shortest line at the bank.
也许我应该押你这匹马
Maybe I should bet on your horse.
你在开玩笑吧 这可不是纸上谈兵
Are you kidding me? These aren't just words.
上面给你提供了各种各样的信息
They give you all this information,
让你全面掌握情况
so you can make an informed decision
-一押即中 -当然
- and beat the odds. - Yes, of course,
所以手拿赛马报的人"都能发财"嘛
And this is why everybody with a racing form is rich.
来吧 是时候下注了
Now come on. It's time to place our bets.
你的决定是什么 曼尼
What's it gonna be, Manny?
两块钱押"君之乡"
$2 on my hometown.
你确定它会赢吗
You really think he's going to win?
我只知道它的眼睛是这么告诉我的
Well, I only know what he tells me with his eyes.
别问我为什么 也许我前世是一匹马
Don't ask me why, but maybe in some previous life, I was a horse.
或者"牛头马嘴"
Or part of a horse.
嘿 艾丽克斯打过电话
Oh, hey, Alex called.
她把手机落在我们这儿了
She left her cell phone here.
她等下会回来取
She's gonna come back and get it.
小卡 你对你的钓鱼奖杯做了什么吗
Cam, did you do something to your fish trophy?
对 我之前忘了它中间那段有趣的部分
Oh, yeah, I forgot about this fun middle part.
它现在看起来像是一只鱼欢快地跃出水面
You see, now it looks like a fish jumping out of the water.
对 刚好盖过了我的光芒
Yeah, right over mine.
我是不是嗅到了酸味 米奇
Do I sense something, Mitch?
只是我的奖杯稍稍高出一点
You know, just because mine's a little taller than yours,
不代表你的奖杯就不受重视了
doesn't make yours any less important.
不 我没有那么想
Oh, no. That's not what I was feeling,
毫无那种自私狭隘的想法
not even a little bit.
天呐 你压根就不想看到我的奖杯被摆出来
Oh, my god. You don't like that I put my trophy up.
我只是觉得有点奇怪
I just think it's a little weird
恰恰在我刚赢回一个奖杯时
that immediately after I win a trophy,
你就把你的陈年旧奖翻出来
You feel the need to dig this thing up
大摇大摆地放在我的奖杯旁边
and plop it down next to mine.
我想你应该知道
I'll have you know
我一直都想把这个奖杯摆出来
that I want to display this for quite some time.
但是我把它装箱放在车库
But I put it in box in the garage
和我的其他奖杯们尘封在一起
with all my other awards--
没错 复数哦 奖杯们-
Yes, award-z--
只是不想刺激从没得过奖的你
Out of courtesy to a sadly award-less you.
你那奖杯太可笑了
It looks ridiculous.
我得的是杰出的专业奖项
Mine is a distinguished professional award
由我的同行颁发给我
given to me by my peers,
而你的呢 是在码头上颁发给你的
and yours was given to you on a pier.
你要知道
Okay, well, for your information,
我得奖的时候排场可大了
when I won this, it was a very big deal.
我在杂货店出席了剪彩仪式和签名会
I cut a ribbon at the grocery store and signed autographs.
"捕鱼能手 卡梅隆·塔克"
"Best fishes, Cameron Tucker"
你知道吗 我也想起来了
Oh, you know what? I just remembered!
我的奖杯也有一个有趣的底座呢
Mine comes with a really fun pedestal, too!
噢 来看看
Oh! Look at that!
如此一来才是正确的等级排序嘛
Oh, and proper hierarchy is restored. Mm-hmm.
除非你突然想起来
Unless you suddenly remember
你的小鱼还戴着一顶高帽
that your fish came with a top hat.
好吧
Okay. you know what?
我要去接莉莉然后去公园
I'm gonna go get Lily from her party and go to the park.
去吧
OK.
得奖后你变了 米切尔
This award has changed you, Mitchell.
你现在飘飘然飞得很高
You may be flying high now,
但很快 你会摔得很惨 汤姆·派迪
but pretty soon, you're gonna be free falling, Tom Petty...
因为你心胸狭隘
Because you're petty.
汤姆·狭隘
Tom Petty.
听懂了吗
Hmm? Get it?
早就懂了
About three sentences ago.
你好啊海莉
Hola, Haley.
嘿 歌洛莉亚 谢谢你能过来
Hi, Gloria. Thanks for coming over.
请说西班牙语
En espanol, por favor.
乃好 歌洛莉亚
Uh, hola, Gloria.
谢谢你"大驾光迎"
Gracias for coming over.
不对 要说完整
No, the whole thing.
我不知道后半句怎么说
I don't know the whole thing.
为什么我要学西班牙语
Why do I even need to learn Spanish?
我住在加州 用不着西班牙语的
I live in california. I'm never gonna use it.
这就是美国人的毛病
That's the problem with Americans.
他们希望所有人都学会说他们的语言
They expect all of us to know their language,
但却不愿意花点精力学学我们的语言
but they don't even make the effort to learn ours.
有本事你们也到处打胜仗啊
Win a war sometime.
那我们就会开始学习你们的语言了
Then we'll start talking like you.
哈 错的离谱
Ha. So wrong.
嘿 歌洛莉亚
Oh, hey, Gloria.
嘿 菲尔 你好吗
Hi, Phil. How are you?
我真希望我知道
I wish I knew.
此话怎讲 发生什么了
Why? What's wrong?
我不希望惹你心烦
Uh, I don't wanna bum you out.
我的医生让我做了些检查
My doctor did some tests
说如果发现什么问题他会打电话
and said he'd call if something was wrong,
今天早上他打了
and he called this morning.
他说了什么
And what did he say?
我不知道 我没有接到那个电话
I don't know. I missed the call.
现在我联系不到他了
Now I can't reach him.
那只黑色老鼠
The black mouse.
-什么 -在我梦里
- What? - In my dream.
是个凶兆
It was a bad omen.
但应该不是冲你来的
But probably not for you.
楼梯
The staircase.
不不不 你没事 你肯定没事的
No, no, no. You're fine. You're fine.
是吗 听着
Am I? Get this --
15年前 我赢了够用一辈子的剃须刀片
15 years ago, I won a lifetime supply of razor blades.
但如今却用完了
They ran out...
就在今天
today.
你吐口水干嘛 驱赶阎王爷吗
What's with the spitting? Are you warding off death?
没有 我刚吸气
No. When I did
好像吸个虫子进嘴了
I think I suck in a little bug.
第一场赢了16 第二场赢了10块
$16 for the first race, $10 from the second race,
再加上34块 一共赢了60啊
plus $34--$60?
老爸你真是天才
You're a genius, dad.
功劳也不都在我
Well, I cannot take all the credit.
今天那些马都很健谈 告诉我很多信息
It is a particularly chatty group of horses today.
赌博我好爱 钞票轻松来
I love gambling! It's so easy!
可没那么轻松
It's not easy.
对连输三场的人来说 当然不轻松
Well, not for you. You've lost, what, three in a row?
怒火中烧吧 杰
Oh, burn, Jay!
抱歉 我不该刺激你的
I'm sorry. That was uncalled for.
赢钱赢得脑袋晕
This is all so heady.
50块押"小培根"赢
$50 on little bacon to win.
啧啧
Ooh-ee.
-是啊 啧啧 -搞什么 你们咂什么嘴
- Yeah, ooh-ee. - What? What ooh-ee?
"小培根"有点不大对劲
There is something not right about that horse.
-我也看出来了 -你看出来个屁
- I think I saw it, too. - You didn't see anything.
"小培根"可是夺冠热门
This horse is a heavy favorite.
其余的还没旋转木马跑得快呢
The rest of the pack couldn't beat a merry-go-round.
我铁了心压"小培根"了
I'm sticking with little bacon.
等着受死吧
It's your funeral.
我们押哪匹 老爸
Who are we going with, dad?
我们不跟 宝贝
Nobody in this race, papito.
刚刚下面马圈里一片寂静无声
It was quiet down there in the paddock just now--
简直万马齐喑
too quiet.
好吧 爷就不信了 给我押三百
Oh, gee. You know what? Make it $300.
下血本啊
Oh, my.
告诉你小子 我此次押的绝对错不了
I'm telling you, kid, this is the one.
想知道为什么吗
And you know how I know?
因为它发出的声音是 "不输"
'cause it said, "pfft."
马才不会发出那种声音
They don't talk like that.
玛利亚为婚礼买了条美丽的白裙子
"Maria bought a beautiful white dress for her wedding."
玛利亚买了条
Um, Maria compro
白色滴裙子
un hermoso vestido blanco
围了... 不好意思
para su-- I-I'm sorry.
他盯着我我没法专心
I cannot concentrate with him here.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
将你的模样永远铭记在心
Just taking it all in.
你是个美丽聪慧的女人
You're a beautiful, intelligent woman...
永远记住这一点
And don't you ever forget it.
他有时候真是脑筋不正常
Wow, he is so weird sometimes.
不 他正常得很 他是个圣人
No, he's not weird! He's a saint!
他一旦去世了你会想念他的
And you will miss him when he's gone...
我是说将来
One day.
米奇尔舅舅好
Hey, uncle Mitchell.
你手机在桌上
Your, uh, phone's on the table.
那是什么
What's that?
小卡以前获得的钓鱼奖杯
Oh, Cam's old fishing trophy.
早上我一睁眼
Yeah, when I woke up this morning,
它就矗在那了
That's where I found it.
就在你把奖杯放那之后吗
Right after you got yours?
谢谢支持
Thank you!
天呐 我们可真是同病相怜
Oh, my god. Welcome to my world.
上周 组织授予我一枚奖章
Last week, I got this beautiful plaque
因为我在辩论队表现极其出色
from the debate team for outstanding achievement,
你知道我妈做了什么吗
and what did my mom do?
她翻出卢克的一条"参与奖"绶带
She found one of Luke's "participant" ribbons
以及海莉的什么"准时签到"证书
and a certificate Haley got for showing up somewhere on time,
然后把那俩玩意儿跟我的放在一个架子上
and put all three of them together on the same shelf!
那含金量能一样吗
It's, like, so unfair!
我很高兴跟艾丽克斯说了这事
I was so glad I talked to Alex,
因为她跟我的感受简直完全一样
because she agreed with every single thing I was feeling--
那让我意识到
which made me realize
我表现得 就像个幼稚少女 羞涩捂脸
that I was acting like a 14-year-old girl.
给点力啊 小破孩
Ah, come on, kid.
你都害我损失了件装备了
I just lost an arm 'cause of you.
给我专心点玩
Now get your head in the game.
抱歉 我爸盯着 我集中不起精神
Sorry. I can't concentrate with my dad staring at me.
我实在太爱你了
I just love you so much.
希望他不是在对我表白
I hope he's talking to you.
这下好了 我死了
Ugh. Oh, great, now I'm dead.
我得去趟洗手间
I'm going to the bathroom.
常言道 生死乃游戏家常事
You know, they say that happens.
嘿 沃特
Hey, Walt.
你有想过死亡吗
You ever think about death?
我都85了 死神天天盯着我呢
I'm 85. Death is my roommate.
医生给我打电话了
I got a call from the doctor.
我有60%的可能性会死
There's a 60% chance I'm gonna die.
哈 可笑的医生
Ha! Doctors--
十年前就说我要死了
said I'd be dead ten years ago.
你看我
Look at me.
依然健康得如同...
I'm healthy as a--
我得去换块电池了
I gotta go change my tank.
菲尔 你得放宽心
Phil, you've gotta let this go.
对不起 克莱尔
I'm sorry, Claire.
我实在是手足无措
I don't know how to react
因为我发现自己有70%的可能会死
when I find out there's a 70% chance I'm gonna die.
亲爱的 听我说
Honey, listen to me.
你不会有事的
You're gonna be fine.
-你真这么想 -我确定
- You really think so? - I know so.
克莱尔是我的后盾
Claire's my rock.
当你在飞机上遇上气流颠簸
You know when you're on a plane and there's turbulence,
你看看那些空姐空少
you look at the flight attendants,
如果他们笑容依旧地端茶倒水
and if they're still smiling and serving drinks,
你就会觉得心安
you know everything's gonna be okay?
克莱尔就像那样
That's Claire.
我也可以把她想象成一名警察
I could also picture her as a cop.
率先进入最后两百米的是"小培根"
And into the final furlong it's little bacon
其次是"布拉德的蜡光皮衣"
followed by Bradswaxjacket
冲啊"小培根" "小培根"冲啊
Go little bacon. Go little bacon.
你可以的 你可以的
You got this! You got this!
冲啊冲啊冲啊
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
冠军是九号"小培根" 领先了三马身的距离
And the winner is NO.9 little bacon by 3 lengths.
太棒了 我就知道
Yes! I knew it!
看到了吗 曼尼 狗屎运没那么多的
You see that, Manny? Dumb luck always runs out.
但如果你脚踏实地
But if you live in the real world,
动动脑子
and you use your head,
而非像怪医杜立德糊涂一世聪明一时
not have it in the clouds like Dr. Dolittle there,
你会赢的
You'll do okay.
或许这次我们应该听杰的 老爸
Guess we should have listened to Jay on this one, dad.
这话没错 不听杰之言 吃亏在眼前
You got that right. You should have listened to Jay.
我还要告诉你
And I'll tell you something else.
光看着马的眼睛
You can't look in a horse's eyes
是看不出个所以然的
and tell there's something wrong.
你甚至无法同时看着马的两只眼睛
You can't even look in their eyes at the same time --
不在一边啊
One's here and one's here!
走吧 我们去窗口领钱
Come on. Let's go to the window, kid.
我一个人可拿不动那么多
I may need some help carrying my winnings.
且慢
Oh. Wait.
杰 你看
Jay, look.
调查中
Inquiry.
那是什么意思
What's that?
就是有匹马违规了
It is when a horse has committed an infraction.
可能违规 通常没什么大碍
Possible infraction. Usually it's nothing.
我确定
I'm sure...
九号马"小培根"
The number 9 horse little bacon
由于"非法阻挡"被取消冠军资格
has been disqualified for interference.
搞什么
What?!
冠军是6号马 "布拉德的蜡光皮衣"
The winner is number 6 bradswaxjacket.
瞧见没
You see?
眼睛
The eyes...
不撒谎
They do not lie.
倒霉啊 杰
Tough break, Jay.
给
Here...
就当是油钱
Little something for gas.
小卡是对的 我太心胸狭隘了
Cam was right. I-I was being petty.
于是我找到他那箱奖杯
So I found his box of old trophies
决定给他惊喜
and I decided to surprise him
等他回家时会发现全摆在壁炉上
by having them on the mantle when he got home.
结果倒是我自己惊讶了一番
Well, I was the one who was surprised.
我完全不知道他得过那么多奖
I had no idea how many trophies he had--
都是第一名 五花八门的
First place, and all of them for different things.
音乐 橄榄球 艺术展 科学展
Music, football, art show, science fair,
美食节
a chili cook-off.
他藏起了人生中全部的荣耀
A lifetime of accolades hidden away
以免我自惭形秽
just so I wouldn't feel bad.
老鼠 有老鼠 好恶心
Aah! That's a mouse! That's a mou--oh! Ew!
太恶心了
Oh! Disgusting!
不 小卡 我是想把奖杯全部展出来
Oh, no! No, cam, I-I was gonna make a big display!
我想"也是"
I believe you have.
你误会了 小卡 里面有只...
No, no, Cam! There was a--
恶心
Oh! Gross!
曼尼 帮我个忙
Listen, Manny, do me a favor
过去帮我买杯卡布奇诺好吗
and get me a cappuccino from right over there, okay?
不用了 我现在是款爷
No, it's okay. I got it.
那个
So...
想聊聊刚才的事吗
You wanna talk about what happened back there?
-完全没兴趣 -其实
- Not at all. - You know...
我以眼观心的本事 不只是针对马
it is not just the horses whose souls I can read through their eyes.
你真想知道吗 我告诉你
You really wanna know? I'll tell you.
好吧 我不烦你了
Okay. I'll leave you alone.
听着 别走
All right, listen, hang on.
很抱歉我在曼尼面前找你麻烦
I'm sorry I went after you like that in front of Manny.
我错了
That was wrong.
不 我懂的 没人愿意输掉比赛
No, I get it. Nobody likes to lose at the races.
我不欠那家伙什么
I don't owe this guy anything.
他一年会来看儿子几次
He stops by a couple of times a year to see his kid.
以前对我来说是种解脱 可以休息下
It used to be a relief, gave me a nice break.
可现在曼尼和我已经情同父子
But now Manny and I, we got our own thing.
我知道自己不是他亲爹
Look, I know I'm not his dad...
但我不喜欢他的到来让我想到那一点
Maybe I don't like the reminder.
-我的天啊 -怎么啦
- Oh! Oh, my gosh! - Hey, what's up?
-怎么啦 -一听到消息我们就来了
- What? - We came as soon as we heard.
什么消息
Heard what?
我们听说菲尔从医生那儿得到了噩耗
We heard Phil got bad news from the doctor.
谁说的
Who told you that?
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
不 我没说他确诊了
No, I didn't say that he got bad news...
我说的是有那个可能
I said that he was getting bad news.
你也只是猜测有可能
You don't know that he's getting bad news.
我看见黑耗子了
I saw a black mouse.
我也看见了
谁信啊
So he says.
-好了各位 -这比我想象的还糟
- Okay. You guys... - Oh, this is worse than I thought!
没事的 听我说
No, it's not. Listen to me. Listen.
菲尔没事 事实上
Phil is fine. As a matter of fact,
在他发现你们之前快闪人吧
you should go before he even knows you're here.
不不 我们不走 我们留下
No, no. We're staying. We're staying.
一听到消息我们就来了
We got here as soon as we could.
有买咖啡蛋糕吗
Did you bring the coffee cake?
有 在我这儿
Yes, I have it right here.
他拿下车而已 我出的钱
He carried it in from the car. I paid for it.
听我说 听着
Listen. Listen to me.
对于你现在所受的煎熬 我深表同情
I am very sorry for what you are going through.
谢谢
Thank you.
这谁啊
Who is this?
何方神圣
Who, indeed?
我是哈维尔·迪尔加多 曼尼的亲爹
I am Javier Delgado, Manny's father
歌洛莉亚的前夫兼爱人
and Gloria's former husband and lover.
我说这话你别觉得我冷血
I hope you do not think this is insensitive,
你是位美丽的女人
but you are a beautiful woman,
再找个男人不难的
and you will have no trouble to find a man--...
哈维尔 人家老公尸骨未寒呢
Javier! The body is not even cold yet!
"行尸"活的好好的 在楼上看篮球比赛呢
The body is upstairs watching basketball.
他没事
He is fine.
-歌洛莉亚说他病了 -没有
- Gloria said he was sick. - No.
他去看了医生 做了些检查
He went to the doctor, he had some tests.
医生来了电话 就是这样
The doctor called. That's it.
加上他终生供应的剃刀 在今天用完了
Plus today he run out of his lifetime supply of razors.
这是个征兆
That's a sign.
全都是无中生有
This is a lot of hocus-pocus!
难以置信我买个蛋糕却用在如此可笑的场合
I can't believe I bought a coffee cake over this!
等等 我有点混乱
Wait, wait, wait, no, no. I'm confused.
医生到底怎么说的
What did the doctor say exactly?
我不知道 今早的电话我们错过了
I don't know. We missed his call this morning.
医生在周六打来电话?
The doctor called on Saturday?
-是的 那又如何 -没什么
- Yeah. So? - Nothing.
有什么 有什么 快说
Not nothing. Not nothing. What?
只是 那个
Well, it's just that, uh,
医生在周六打电话 通常没好事
Doctors don't usually call on Saturday with good news
但是可能...
But they could call--
可能是因为其它事情
I mean, he could call with anything.
你觉得他真病了吗
Do you think he's sick...
这是 怎么回事
What's... what going on?
没什么 大家来串个门
Nothing. Nothing. Everybody just came by
没什么特别原因
for absolutely no reason at all.
你一脸担心的样子
You look worried.
我没担心
I'm not worried.
天呐 飞机失事前
Oh, god. The plane's in trouble.
空姐会收好小餐车 大家扣好安全带
You put away the drink cart and you're strapping in.
-你会没事的 孩子 -肯定没事的
- You're gonna be fine, kid! - You are gonna be great!
你气色比我还好呢
I wish I looked this good.
拜托别说了 胆都被你们吓破了
Stop, please! You're freaking me out.
你会死吗
Are you gonna die?
我不知道 我有5%的机会可以挺过去
I don't know! There's stil a 5% chance I'll make it!
-是桑德弗医生 -接吧
- It's Dr. Sendroff. - Okay. Okay.
亲人们 我不知道电话
Guys, I don't know what's on
那端会是什么消息
the other end of this phone call...
但无论发生何事 只希望大家知道
But whatever happens, I just want you to know,
你们已经给了我终生用不完的幸福
you've already given me a lifetime supply of happiness.
我记得小时候
I remember once as a child--
-接电话呀 -快接
- Answer it! - Do it!
桑德弗医生
Dr. Sendroff?
找我什么事
What's the word?
-真的吗 -什么
- Are you serious? - What?
是这样吗
That's it?
是怎么样
What is it?!
等等
H-hold on one second.
他打电话是问房子挂牌的事 我没事
He's calling about a real estate listing. I'm fine.
就这个啊
Ay, no.
昨天 你说有问题的话会打电话
Yesterday, you said you'd call if something was wrong.
你打了电话 接着就消失了
Then you called, then you disappeared.
这是我这辈子见过的最不负责任
That is the most irresponsible, unprofessional thing
最没职业水准的事
I've ever heard of in my entire life!
你想出售的房子
And do you have anyone to represent you
现在找好经纪人了吗
in the sale of your current house?
我以眼观心过了
Look into his eyes.
无论医生说什么
I don't care what the doctor says.
我看他就半年命了
I give him six months.
别盯着人家看
Stop staring.
菲尔·邓菲 介绍下你自己
So, Phil Ddunphy, tell us a little bit about yourself.
奇普 我娶了个好老婆 克莱尔
Well, Chip, I'm married to a great lady--hi, Claire!
有个宝贝女儿
And I have a baby girl.
我是个房产经纪人 喜欢下跳棋
Um, I'm a real estate agent, and I enjoy playing checkers.
-好的 -中式西式跳棋都喜欢
- Okay. - Both chinese and american.
还有 我超粉嘻哈风
And, uh, I am a fan of hip-hop.
不错
Well, good for you.
不过在东西岸嘻哈大对决中 我尽量保持中立
Though I try to stay neutral in the whole east coast/west coast thang.
-下一位... -马上说完
- Next up we have a-- - One quick thing--
向我的大学哥们林问个好
Shout out to my, uh, college buddy Ling,
他自己造了架直升机 今天首航
who built his own helicopter and is taking his first flight today,
我还要祝岳父岳母大人
and, uh, I also wanna wish a happy anniversary
杰·普里契特伉俪结婚周年快乐
to my in-laws Jay and Dede Pritchett.
你们至死不渝的爱情给后辈作了好榜样
Your eternal love is an inspiration to us all.
好了 说够了吧
Okay. That's enough.
下一位 来自宾州怀斯特米福的家庭主妇
Next up, we have a homemaker from West Mifflin, Pennsylvania.
你好
Hi.